Guide to the John Kent Folmar's Collection on the Monongahela River Buffs Association, 1870-2015 AIS.2019.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- The Voice of the Mon, 1979-2015; IX.
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 26, Issue 1-2, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 27, Issue 1-2, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 28, Issue 1, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 29, Issue 1-2, 2010 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 30, Issue 1-2, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 31, Issue 1, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 32, Issue 1-2, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 33, Issue 1, 2014 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - The Voice of the Mon, Volume 34, Issue 1, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Topical, 1897-1981; X.
  Papers related to various aspects of the Monongahela and Allegheny Rivers, as well as the riverboats and riverboat workers on them.
  - Allegheny River, List of Bridges, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Edward Pershing Crosbie, License, January 29, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - H. R. 6479 – An Act to Provide for the Licensing of Personnel on Certain, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Homestead Consolidated Enrollment and License, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Inspection Circular No. 5-62, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - James Rees & Sons Company Works print, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Reproduction Prints of Steamboats, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - River Buff's Museum Artwork, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - River Transportation Timelines, 1917-1926 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rosters of Various Riverboat Workers, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Steamer Tom Dodsworth, Certificate of Inspection, September, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Terminals, Allegheny and Monongahela Rivers, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - US Army Corps of Engineers, Barge Mooring Width Restrictions Monongahela and Ohio Rivers, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - William D. Britton, Chief Engineer License, July 23, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- United States Steel and Organized Labor Unions, 1923-1992; XI.
  Papers related to United States Steel (including the companies that were absorbed to create US Steel, such as Carnegie Steel) and Organized Labor Unions related to steel working and more specifically, the riverboat workers connected to the steel industry.
  - Crew member rosters, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - International Longshoremen's Association, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - List of Eligible Voters, National Labor Relations Board, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Lists of vessels used at Clairton Works, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - National Maritime Union of America, 1955-1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - National Organization of Master, Mates, and Pilots of America, 1944-1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Marine Engineers Beneficial Association letter, February 12, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Seniority Lists, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Wage Calculation Monthly Rates by Position, Carnegie Steel Company, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Video Interviews, 1984-1994; XII.
  This series contains video recordings conducted by John K. Folmar with various people who were employed with riverboat-related jobs as well as a former vice president of California University. The interviews are from 1984 to 1994 and are stored on DVDs.
  - Acting Lockmaster Bob Smith interview with John K. Folmar DVD, January 7, 1990 (Box 16, Disc 1)
  - Captain Leo Hughes interview with John K. Folmar DVD, February 8, 1990 (Box 16, Disc 2)
  - Captain Clyde Aston interview with John K. Folmar DVD, May 3, 1990 (Box 16, Disc 3)
  - Former California University Vice President Merrill interview with John K. Folmar DVD, undated (Box 16, Disc 4)
  - Jack Gordon interview with John K. Folmar DVD, April 30, 1987 (Box 16, Disc 5)
  - Monongahela River Boat Ride on the Liberty Bell with commentary by Wink McCormick Part 1: From California, Pennsylvania to Rice's Landing DVD, October 5, 1989 (Box 16, Disc 6)
  - Monongahela River Boat Ride on the Liberty Bell with commentary by Wink McCormick Part 2: From Rice's Landing to Lock 7 DVD, October 5, 1989 (Box 16, Disc 7)
  - Monongahela River Boat Ride on the Liberty Bell with commentary by Wink McCormick Part 3: From Lock 7 to Morgantown, West Virginia DVD, October 5, 1989 (Box 16, Disc 8)
  - Tom McFarlane interview with John K. Folmar DVD, April 19, 1994 (Box 16, Disc 9)
  - Walter A. Smith, Jr. interview with John K. Folmar DVD, December 18, 1984 (Box 16, Disc 10)